#### Contact

esfinge3@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/andreiabaldin (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Inglês

Trabalho em equipe Resolução de problemas

### Languages

English (Full Professional)
Spanish (Full Professional)
Portuguese (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

Industry 4.0 Fundamentals
ITIL® 4 Foundation
Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC)

# Andreia Baldin

Global IT Governance, Quality and Services Leader for AMERICAS at Unilever | ITIL | Scrum | COBIT | DevOps | LeanIT | Cloud Campinas, São Paulo, Brazil

## Summary

IT Leader, 27 years of professional experience. I have been working for fifteen years in order to drive and manage IT Infrastructure improvements through projects and running activities.

GovOps/DevOps/LeanIT/Agile/ITIL/COBIT frameworks/tools/ concepts covering Printing, Cloud, Docusign, Network - WAN, LAN, Voice, WIFi, SDWAN, etc., focusing sharply on continuous service excellence, stakeholder management, quality and IT & Business´ Strategies over different Digital Transformation journeys (Performance & Sustainability´s Cultures).

These activities include: leadership and negotiation teams, creating/refining processes as well as coordinating IT projects. Also, supporting running (BAU) activities in a multicultural (global) perspective, in accomplishing of agreed SLAs (ITIL 4 certified) and minimizing business' impacts. Ensure high quality level and the final customer, stakeholder and business' satisfaction, in parallel of reducing costs under different scopes/goals.

By the end, I had almost two years as telecommunications analyst, five ones as support analyst (Portuguese, English and Spanish) in IT and six years in management/organizations of events/Marketing, working on international and national companies.

# Experience

Unilever

15 years 11 months

IT Governance, Operations and Service Quality Leader - AMERICAS May 2019 - Present (4 years 5 months)

São Paulo Area, Brazil

Lead of IT Governance & Services lifecycle for AMERICAS region, covering:

- E2E Print Services Management/Refresh/Support;
- Adoption of new Digital Platforms (Docusign, Cloud, etc) in accordance with business' needs;
- Cross-work among different global regions;
- Contribution for cost reduction/savings over different scenarios/countries;
- Point of Contact for Stakeholders and Supplier/Vendor(s);
- Service Improvement Plan and Innovation projects implementation (DevOps/GovOps);
- Full support and/or leadership of different IT transformation jorneys;
- Ensure total quality of service and internal business' satisfaction (SLAs, ITIL, LeanIT, COBIT5, etc).

IT Coordinator (Infrastructure) - Geography Business Partner July 2014 - April 2019 (4 years 10 months)

E2E coordination/management of:

- local IT Infrastructure Projects
- leading with changes, incidents and problems
- optimization and simplification of processes and procedures
- liaison between Business and IT Partners
- driving improvements on IT infrastructure in Factories and Distribution Centers
- controlling the SLA/ making KPI's
- focusing on IT Strategy and Performance Culture

IT Coordinator - Network Service Quality (Infrastructure)
November 2007 - June 2014 (6 years 8 months)
Unilever

Liaison among different teams of Network Services lifecycle:

- E2E Network Services Management
- Vendor relationships
- Full support to transform organization and services as well as ensuring SLAs (ITIL)
- Ensure total quality of service and internal business' satisfaction

Connectcom / Spread Informatica (resident on Caixa Economica Federal bank)

Telecommunication Analyst 2005 - 2007 (2 years)

Chiptek Informatica (resident on Lucent Technologies company)
Support Analyst

2002 - 2005 (3 years)

Grupo TMS (resident on Promon company) Support Analyst 2000 - 2002 (2 years)

Vertical Eventos Coordinator and operator of Events 1996 - 2000 (4 years)

## Education

UNIP - Universidade Paulista

MBA - pos-graduation, Business Logistics and Supply Chain · (2010 - 2011)

Metrocamp

MBA - pos-graduation, Master Business Administration · (2005 - 2006)

UNIP - Universidade Paulista

Graduation, Analysis of Systems · (1994 - 1998)